Donald and Charlotte MacJannet Papers MS024
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Donald and Charlotte MacJannet Papers
1920 -- 1990
1824 -- 2003
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
MacJannet Blensdorf, Charlotte
MacJannet, Donald Ross
MS024
99.75 Linear Feet
2 Volumes
60 Audiovisual Object(s)
729 Digital Object(s)
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into nine series: Personal papers; Camp records and correspondence; Schools, Records and correspondence; MacJannet Foundation; Talloires/Priory; Tufts; Photographs and other media; MacJannet Legacy Oral History Interviews and donated items of memory, 2002-2003
Biographical / Historical
Donald Ross MacJannet (1894-1986), A1916, H1933, H1979, was a benefactor of Tufts University and an educator who established his own international schools and camps. His greatest gift to the Tufts was the property in Talloires, France which the university uses as the European Center.
A descendent of Peregrine White, the baby born on the Mayflower, MacJannet was orphaned at an early age and raised, along with his sister, in the home of a Medford, Massachusetts widow. In 1912, he graduated as valedictorian of Medford High School and entered Tufts College on a partial scholarship. He earned a B.A. in French literature in 1916. He then attended the Sorbonne in France. During World War I he trained as a pilot.
In 1925, MacJannet founded a school in Paris, known as the Trocadero School. He then opened a second school in St. Cloud, called the Elms School, where students of all nationalities were educated, Prince Philip, the Duke of Edinburgh, among them. He also acquired some land near Lake Annency the following year. There he started two camps, one for girls and the other for boys, which attracted an international clientele, spreading his reputation as an educator throughout the world. Some of his notable campers include Indira Gandhi, the late Prime Minister of India, and Supreme Court Justice Potter Stewart.
In 1932, MacJannet was elected to the Legion of Honor. This was also the year he met a young German woman named Charlotte Blensdorf (1901-1999), a teacher of the Dalcroze method, at an educational conference in Nice, France. They married November 5, 1932 in the Marylebone Town Hall in London. The MacJannet schools operated for seventeen years, closing in the early 1940s. The camps continued until 1964, with a brief hiatus during World War II. During the war, the MacJannets returned to the United States, operating a school and camp in Idaho and helping with the war effort in Washington, D.C. In 1944, they established the Vacation School of French with Tufts College. Located in Arlington, MA, the purpose of the summer school was to educate people in French language and culture so that they might take up rehabilitation work in post-war France.
In 1944, Tufts president Leonard Carmichael called on the MacJannets to help consolidate the college's dental and medical schools on the new Harrison Avenue, Boston campus. As soon as they were able, the MacJannets returned to France to resume their camps' normal operations. This work also involved aid to French orphans, children who were the camp's first attendees after the war.
The MacJannets purchased an eleventh century Benedictine priory in Talloires, France in 1958. MacJannet restored the building for use as an educational facility, using it for twenty years as a center to house educational and cultural events, drawing people from around the world. In 1979, the MacJannets turned the property over to Tufts University, which established its European campus and conference center on the premises. The MacJannets split their time thereafter between Talloires and their home in Geneva.
Donald MacJannet died on April 4, 1986 in Geneva, Switzerland. Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet continued the work they had begun together until her death in 1999.
Custodial History
This bulk of this collection was sent from Charlotte MacJannet in her home in Geneva, shipped by John H. King, and arrived at Tufts in late 2001.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains the correspondence and papers of Donald and Charlotte MacJannet covering their lives from the end of the 19th century to the end of the 20th century. Their lives were touched by the major events of the 20th century and their papers reflect the world around them. Personal papers and records of the camps and schools they founded in Europe and America are included, as well as material relating to the Priory at Talloires and Tufts College/Tufts University. This collection contains film, photographs, correspondence, ledgers, admissions files, student files, scrapbooks, and other materials that reflect their lives, both personal and professional. Their personal papers also include information about their professional endeavors, including information about their camps and schools.
MacJannet, Donald Ross; MacJannet, Charlotte Blensdor; Foster, Jean MacJannet; Foster, Emory; MacJannet School (The Elms); MacJannet Camp; European Center; MacJannet School (Sun Valley) --MacJannet Camp; Talloires (France); Students --Schools --World War, 1939-1945; St. Cloud (France); University history; Teaching and learning; Alumni collections
- Personal papers, 1824 -- 1999; 1916 -- 1986; MS024.001; 27.9 Linear Feet; 1 Volumes; 2 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the correspondence, papers, family documents, calendars and souvenirs of the MacJannets from 1825 to 1999. The material covers not only the personal events in their lives, but many of the great events of the 20th century, including for example early MacJannet family diaries (1825), letters concerning Charlotte MacJannet's family in Germany after WWII, correspondence concerning prison camps in WWII France and letters about apartheid in the 1970s. Also includes correspondence with such 'notables' as Prince Philip, Duke of Edinburgh, Indira Gandhi, Eleanor Roosevelt and Dwight Eisenhower. Also included is family correspondence with members of the MacJannet Clan in the UK, South Africa, Canada and Australia. As part of this series the personal papers of Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet and Donald MacJannet's sister, Jean Foster, are included. Due to many interests of the MacJannets, some of these papers also touch on such issues as the schools and camp.
  Arrangement
  Papers are by subject and then alphabetically within a box. Folders often contain the material from an original folder. Titles of folder often reflect original folder title.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Centre International des Amis de la musique, 1995; MS024.001.130.00001 (Box 130)
    Material relating to Charlotte MacJannet's involvement with the organization. Also includes correspondence.
  - Centre International des Amis de la musique, 1995; MS024.001.130.00002 (Box 130)
  - Centre International des Amis de la musique, 1995; MS024.001.130.00003 (Box 130)
  - Centre International des Amis de la musique, 1995; MS024.001.130.00004 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00005 (Box 130)
    Charlotte MacJannet's correspondence with Gerda Alexander, a teacher of Eutonia.
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00006 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00007 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00008 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00009 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00010 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00011 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00012 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00013 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00014 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00016 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00017 (Box 130)
  - Correspondence with Gerda, 1960; MS024.001.130.00018 (Box 130)
  - Europa Union, 1992; MS024.001.130.00019 (Box 130)
    Material in German.
  - Eutonia, MS024.001.130.00020 (Box 130)
  - "What is Eutonia?", 1960; MS024.001.130.00021 (Box 130)
  - Writings on Eutonia, 1960; MS024.001.130.00022 (Box 130)
  - Material on Eutonia, 1968; MS024.001.130.00023 (Box 130)
  - Material on Eutonia, 1968; MS024.001.130.00024 (Box 130)
    Includes letters.
  - Gerda Alexander's course at the Priory, 1961; MS024.001.130.00025 (Box 130)
    Includes correspondence and course material.
  - Gerda Alexander's course at the Priory, 1967; MS024.001.130.00026 (Box 130)
  - Gerda Alexander's course at the Priory, 1967; MS024.001.130.00027 (Box 130)
  - Girl Scouts, 1991; MS024.001.130.00028 (Box 130)
  - Otto Blensdorf, 1920; MS024.001.130.00029 (Box 130)
    Material on Otto Blensdorf, the father of Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet and teacher of the Dalcroze method Rythmique.
  - Personal papers Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet, 1950; MS024.001.130.00030 (Box 130)
    Includes letters and souvenirs.
  - Personal papers Charlotte Blesndorf MacJannet: notebooks, 1920 -- 1930; MS024.001.130.00031 (Box 130)
    Notebooks of music and jottings.
  - Personal papers Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet, 1920; MS024.001.130.00032 (Box 130)
    Inlcudes letters and souvenirs. Also inludes copy of publication of "Le Rythme" by C. B. MacJannet in "La Nouvelle Education" February 1933.
  - Personal papers Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet, 1920 -- 1950; MS024.001.130.00033 (Box 130)
  - Pipes, 1950; MS024.001.130.00034 (Box 130)
    Material relating to C. B. MacJannet's involvement with the various Pipe (flute, recorder) associations, inlcuding the Pipers Guild, Guilde francaise des faiseurs et joueurs de pipeau and La guilde suisse des flutes de bambou.
  - Pipes, 1950; MS024.001.130.00035 (Box 130)
    Material (music scores included) relating to C. B. MacJannet's involvement with the various Pipe (flute, recorder) associations, inlcuding the Pipers Guild, Guilde francaise des faiseurs et joueurs de pipeau and La guilde suisse des flutes de bambou.
  - Pipes, 1950; MS024.001.130.00036 (Box 130)
  - Pipes, 1930 -- 1960; MS024.001.130.00037 (Box 130)
  - Pipes, 1930 -- 1960; MS024.001.130.00038 (Box 130)
  - Pipes, 1930 -- 1960; MS024.001.130.00039 (Box 130)
  - Pipes, 1930 -- 1960; MS024.001.130.00040 (Box 130)
  - Pipes, 1930 -- 1960; MS024.001.130.00041 (Box 130)
  - Priory papers, 1969; MS024.001.130.00042 (Box 130)
    Material relating to Priory concerts organized by C. B. MacJannet.
  - American Legion Auxilary, Jean MacJannet Foster, 1947; MS024.001.131.00001 (Box 131)
  - American Legion Auxilary, Jean MacJannet Foster, 1947; MS024.001.131.00002 (Box 131)
  - Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet, 1930; MS024.001.131.00003 (Box 131)
  - Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet: diplomas, 1925; MS024.001.131.00004 (Box 131)
    Inlcudes diplomas from Thuring Landesheilanftalten and the University at Jena,
  - Correspondence, 1960; MS024.001.131.00005 (Box 131)
    In German.
  - Correspondence, Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet, 1960; MS024.001.131.00006 (Box 131)
  - Correspondence with Blensdorf family, 1980 -- 1986; MS024.001.131.00007 (Box 131)
    Letters pertain to the search for the three children of Ernst Muller-Blensdorf and Ilse Belansdorf (sister of Charlotte) after the death of their mother. Donald and Charlotte MacJannet had lost touch with them during and after WWII when they had fled from Norway to Great Britain. Jane Blensdorf is the second wife of Ernst Muller-Blensdorf.
  - Correspondence with Blensdorf family, 1948; MS024.001.131.00008 (Box 131)
    In German
  - Correspondence "with elders", 1920 -- 1948; MS024.001.131.00009 (Box 131)
  - Correspondence "with elders" of Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet, 1920 -- 1948; MS024.001.131.00010 (Box 131)
  - Diaries, 1960s, Jean MacJannet Foster, MS024.001.131.00011 (Box 131)
  - Diaries, 1970s, Jean MacJannet Foster, MS024.001.131.00012 (Box 131)
  - Diaries, 1980s, Jean MacJannet Foster, MS024.001.131.00013 (Box 131)
  - Diary, year by year, Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet, 1925 -- 1928; MS024.001.131.00014 (Box 131)
  - Diary, year by year, Jean MacJannet Foster, 1925; MS024.001.131.00015 (Box 131)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution, 1950; MS024.001.131.00016 (Box 131)
  - Eutonia, 1984; MS024.001.131.00017 (Box 131)
  - Eutonia, Gerda Alexander, 1970; MS024.001.131.00018 (Box 131)
  - Eutonie/Gerda Alexander, 1990; MS024.001.131.00019 (Box 131)
  - Eutonie/Gerda Alexander, 1990; MS024.001.131.00020 (Box 131)
  - Eutonia/Gerda Alexander, 1990; MS024.001.131.00021 (Box 131)
  - Gerda, 1967 -- 1970; MS024.001.131.00022 (Box 131)
  - Gerda, general, Institute in Copenhagen, 1965; MS024.001.131.00023 (Box 131)
  - Hans-Wolff von Ponickau, 1920 -- 1950; MS024.001.131.00024 (Box 131)
  - Hans-Wolff von Ponickau, artwork, 1940; MS024.001.131.00025 (Box 131)
  - Invitations, Paris, Jean MacJannet Foster, 1940; MS024.001.131.00026 (Box 131)
  - Letters, 1920 -- 1980; MS024.001.131.00027 (Box 131)
  - Letters received by Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet, 1961; MS024.001.131.00028 (Box 131)
  - Letters, Blensdorf family, 1987; MS024.001.131.00029 (Box 131)
  - Letters from Jean Foster to D. and C. MacJannet, 1967; MS024.001.131.00030 (Box 131)
  - Letters to Jean, 1966; MS024.001.131.00031 (Box 131)
  - Notebook Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet, Lund, 1924; MS024.001.131.00032 (Box 131)
  - Notebooks, Blensdorf family history, 1970; MS024.001.131.00033 (Box 131)
  - Notebooks, Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet, 1960; MS024.001.131.00034 (Box 131)
  - Notebook, rythmique exercises, C.B. MacJannet, 1960; MS024.001.131.00035 (Box 131)
  - Personal material Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet, 1970; MS024.001.131.00036 (Box 131)
  - Pipes, 1937; MS024.001.131.00037 (Box 131)
  - Pipes, 1950; MS024.001.131.00038 (Box 131)
  - Pipes, 1950; MS024.001.131.00039 (Box 131)
  - Pipes, 1950; MS024.001.131.00040 (Box 131)
  - "Our ties with Quakers," notebook, 1960; MS024.001.131.00041 (Box 131)
  - Rythmique/Dalcroze, 1987; MS024.001.131.00042 (Box 131)
  - Rythmique, Dalcroze, 1990; MS024.001.131.00043 (Box 131)
  - Rythmique/Dalcroze Society of America, 1990; MS024.001.131.00044 (Box 131)
  - Rythmique/Dalcroze, 1960 -- 1990; MS024.001.131.00045 (Box 131)
    Includes Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet's notebook transcripts of correspondence between Jacques Dlacroze and Adolphe Appia
  - Rythmique/Dalcroze, 1960 -- 1990; MS024.001.131.00046 (Box 131)
  - Rythmique/Dalcroze Interlochen, 1967; MS024.001.131.00047 (Box 131)
  - Rythmique/Dalcroze, 1980; MS024.001.131.00048 (Box 131)
  - Rythmique/Eutonia 'Travaille', 1950; MS024.001.131.00049 (Box 131)
  - Rythmique, 1980; MS024.001.131.00050 (Box 131)
  - Rythmique, 1955; MS024.001.131.00051 (Box 131)
  - Rythmique/Dalcroze, 1983; MS024.001.131.00052 (Box 131)
  - Rythmique, 1990; MS024.001.131.00053 (Box 131)
  - Rythmique/Dalcroze, correspondence and papers, 1990; MS024.001.131.00054 (Box 131)
  - Sigharstein castle, 1990; MS024.001.131.00055 (Box 131)
  - Blensdorf material, 1950; MS024.001.132.00001 (Box 132)
    Newspaper clippings, letters and notebooks on Otto Blensdorf and Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet.
  - Correspondence, 1955; MS024.001.132.00002 (Box 132)
    Correspondence of Charlotte MacJannet.
  - Correspondence with Blensdorf family, 1950 -- 1960; MS024.001.132.00003 (Box 132)
    Correspondence with Charlotte MacJannet's mother and other family members.
  - Correspondence with Ilse, 1920 -- 1960; MS024.001.132.00004 (Box 132)
    Ilse Blensdorf, sister to Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet.
  - Eurythmics, Ania Antik, 1950; MS024.001.132.00005 (Box 132)
    Material on eurythmics - another name/form of rythmique - collected by Charlotte MacJannet.
  - Eutonie, 1970; MS024.001.132.00006 (Box 132)
    Letters and material on Eutonia.
  - Eutonia, 1960; MS024.001.132.00007 (Box 132)
    Includes "Origin of the word Eutonia."
  - Eutonie Congress, Copenhagen, 1959; MS024.001.132.00008 (Box 132)
    Material concerning the International Society of Eutonie's congress in 1959.
  - "Father's work," Otto Blensdorf, 1948; MS024.001.132.00009 (Box 132)
    Material on Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet's father.
  - Gerda Alexander's July course, Priory, 1960; MS024.001.132.00010 (Box 132)
    Summer course given by Gerda Alexander.
  - Gerda Alexander's course B, Priory, 1961; MS024.001.132.00011 (Box 132)
  - Gerda Alexander's course, Priory, 1961; MS024.001.132.00012 (Box 132)
  - Hans-Wolff von Ponickau, letters, 1955; MS024.001.132.00013 (Box 132)
    Hans-Wollf von Ponickau, artist and friend of Charlotte MacJannet.
  - Hans-Wolff von Ponickau, letters to Dr. H. Bohner, 1920 -- 1958; MS024.001.132.00014 (Box 132)
    Letters from H-W v. Ponickau to Dr. H Bohner (in Japan) sent to Charlotte B. MacJannet
  - Hans-Wolff von Ponickau, letters to Dr. H. Bohner, 1935; MS024.001.132.00015 (Box 132)
  - Hans-Wolff von Ponickau, letters and artwork, 1955; MS024.001.132.00016 (Box 132)
    Includes the fairy tale illustrated post cards by von Ponickau.
  - Hans-Wolff von Ponickau, letters, 1920 -- 1938; MS024.001.132.00017 (Box 132)
    H-W von Ponickau: illustrator and artist.
  - Hjalmar Gullberg, 1995; MS024.001.132.00018 (Box 132)
    Work by Charlotte B. MacJannet and Anders Palm on the poet Hjalmar Gullberg.
  - Hjalmar Gullberg, 1930 -- 1990; MS024.001.132.00019 (Box 132)
  - Letters from Ernst Muller-Blensdorf, 1935; MS024.001.132.00020 (Box 132)
    Letters to Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet from her brother-in-law sculptor Ernst Muller-Blensdorf.
  - Letters to Jean MacJannet Foster, 1960 -- 1975; MS024.001.132.00021 (Box 132)
  - Letters to Jean MacJannet Foster from Donald and Charlotte MacJannet, undated, 1964 -- 1972; MS024.001.132.00022 (Box 132)
  - Otto Blensdorf, 1928; MS024.001.132.00023 (Box 132)
    Material about and by Otto Blensdorf.
  - Otto Blensdorf, scrapbook pages, 1925; MS024.001.132.00024 (Box 132)
  - Charlotte Blensdorf [MacJannet], 1920; MS024.001.132.00024.04205; Unknown (Box 132)
    2 x 3. In MS024/001-132#24 scrapbook.
    People; Donald and Charlotte MacJannet, papers; photographic print; MacJannet, Charlotte Blensdorf
  - Charlotte Blensdorf [MacJannet] with friends, 1923; MS024.001.132.00024.04207; Unknown (Box 132)
    3 x 5. In MS024/001-132#24 scrapbook.
  - Personal file - Blensdorf, 1900 -- 1920; MS024.001.132.00025 (Box 132)
    Includes Otto Blensdorf's diplomas in the Dalcroze/Rythmique method.
  - Personal file - Blensdorf, 1920 -- 1970; MS024.001.132.00026 (Box 132)
  - Personal file, Blensdorf, 1920 -- 1970; MS024.001.132.00027 (Box 132)
  - Rythmique/Dalcroze, Interlochen, Michigan, 1967; MS024.001.132.00028 (Box 132)
    Material from meeting of Rythmique/Dalcroze associations at Interlochen.
  - Rythmique/Dalcroze, 1985; MS024.001.132.00029 (Box 132)
  - Rythmique, 1985; MS024.001.132.00030 (Box 132)
  - Rythmique, 1965; MS024.001.132.00031 (Box 132)
  - Rythmique, 1930; MS024.001.132.00032 (Box 132)
    Early work by Charlotte Blensdorf MacJannet on rythmique
  - Rythmique, 1990; MS024.001.132.00033 (Box 132)
  - Rythmique, 1935; MS024.001.132.00034 (Box 132)
    Includes material on the "Blensdorf-schule fur rythmik" the school of rythmique run by Otto Blensdorf.
  - Rythmique (C. B. MacJannet's early work), 1935; MS024.001.132.00035 (Box 132)
  - Catalogues: Elizabeth Saunders Home, 1965; MS024.001.133.00001 (Box 133)
    The Elizabeth Saunders Home was run by Miki Sawada in Japan. It was a home for children of Japanese and American descent fathered by American GIs.
  - Correspondence Jean MacJannet Foster and Donald and Charlotte MacJannet, 1920 -- 1948; MS024.001.133.00002 (Box 133)
  - Correspondence Jean Foster and Donald and Charlotte MacJannet, 1948 -- 1960; MS024.001.133.00003 (Box 133)
  - Correspondence with Jack and Philip Rich, 1985; MS024.001.133.00004 (Box 133)
    Includes information on Tufts 'takeover' of the Priory and Philip Rich's involvement with this.
  - Correspondence with Jack Rich, 1970; MS024.001.133.00005 (Box 133)
  - Correspondence with Jack Rich, 1955; MS024.001.133.00006 (Box 133)
  - Correspondence with Jack Rich, 1960; MS024.001.133.00007 (Box 133)
  - Correspondence with Jacobs, 1980; MS024.001.133.00008 (Box 133)
    Herbert Jacobs, writer and professor from Berkeley, CA who undertook to write the biography of Donald MacJannet's life.
  - Correspondence with Jacobs, 1980; MS024.001.133.00009 (Box 133)
  - Correspondence with Jacobs, 1980; MS024.001.133.00010 (Box 133)
  - Correspondence with Jacobs, 1980; MS024.001.133.00011 (Box 133)
  - Correspondence with Leon Belmont, 1937 -- 1938; MS024.001.133.00012 (Box 133)
    Donald MacJannet's correspondence with Leon Belmont in Talloires.
  - Donald MacJannet's interview with Professor Seymour Simches, 1979; MS024.001.133.00013 (Box 133)
    Interview by Tufts Professor Simches of D. MacJannet at MacJannet's home in Geneva.
  - Exhibit paintings and film, Sawada, Paris, 1960; MS024.001.133.00014 (Box 133)
    Material from the exhibit of the Elizabeth Saunders Home (run by Miki Sawada) children. Jean Foster was very supportive of the home and work done by Mrs. Sawada.
  - "Family" written by Irene F. Waters MacJannet, 1882; MS024.001.133.00015 (Box 133)
    A book of "Happy Thoughts" written in 1882 by Irene MacJannet, mother of Donald MacJannet, and given to Josephine MaJannet by her borthers, Donald and Malcolm MacJannet, on May 15, 1914.
  - Halsey correspondence, 1975 -- 1977; MS024.001.133.00016 (Box 133)
    James Halsey, teacher/couselor at MacJannet schools and camp, second president of the University of Bridgeport, CT.
  - Halsey correspondence, 1975 -- 1977; MS024.001.133.00017 (Box 133)
    James Halsey, teacher/counselor at MacJannet schools and camp, second president of the University of Bridgeport, CT.
  - Halsey correspondence, 1978 -- 1982; MS024.001.133.00018 (Box 133)
  - Jacobs manuscript, chapters 1-5, 1985; MS024.001.133.00019 (Box 133)
    Manuscript (often with marginalia by Donald MacJannet) of the biography of Donald MacJannet by Herbert Jacobs.
  - Jacobs manuscript, chapters 6-8, 1985; MS024.001.133.00020 (Box 133)
  - Jacobs manuscript, chapters 9-11, 1985; MS024.001.133.00021 (Box 133)
  - Jacobs' questionnaires, 1982; MS024.001.133.00022 (Box 133)
    Questionnaires (and some answers) distributed by Herbert Jacobs regarding life of Donald MacJannet to MacJannet himself and friends.
  - Japan, mementos of trip, 1959; MS024.001.133.00023 (Box 133)
    Mementos kept by Jean MacJannet Foster.
  - Japan, mementos of trip, 1959; MS024.001.133.00024 (Box 133)
  - Jean MacJannet Foster, condolences on death of Emory Foster, 1938; MS024.001.133.00025 (Box 133)
    Letters and cards received by Jean MacJannet Foster on the sudden death of her husband Emory Foster in April 1938 in Chenonceaux, France. The couple were returning from a trip to the Basque region when Foster died suddenly.
  - Jean MacJannet Foster, condolences on death of Emory Foster, 1938; MS024.001.133.00026 (Box 133)
  - Jean MacJannet Foster, condolences on death of Emory Foster, 1938; MS024.001.133.00027 (Box 133)
  - Jean MacJannet Foster, condolences on death of Emory Foster, 1938; MS024.001.133.00028 (Box 133)
  - Jean MacJannet Foster, letters, 1940; MS024.001.133.00029 (Box 133)
  - Letters to Donald MacJannet, 1930; MS024.001.133.00030 (Box 133)
  - Letters and mementos to be kept, 1940; MS024.001.133.00031 (Box 133)
    Includes the letter from Eleanor Roosevelt to the MacJannets, as well as a letter from the office of HRH of Norway.
  - Letters from famous students and campers, 1970; MS024.001.133.00032 (Box 133)
    Includes letters from Elms student Prince Philip and camper Indira Gandhi.